Guide to the Benjamin Shackelford Papers 1913-1915
University of Chicago Library
Shackelford, Benjamin. Papers
1913-1915
.5 linear (1 box)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Benjamin Shackelford, student. The Benjamin Shackelford papers consist of lecture notes taken while Shackelford was a graduate student in Physics at the University of Chicago (1915-1917). The collection includes notes from classes given by Frederick Lindemann, Albert Abraham Michelson, Robert Andrews Millikan, Arthur Lunn, and Gilbert Bliss.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Biographical Note
Benjamin Estill Shackelford was born in Richmond, Montana. He received his A.B. from the University of Montana in 1912. Shackelford went on to study mathematics and physics at the University of Chicago, receiving his Ph.D. In 1916 under the direction of Robert Milliken. Shackelford's thesis was titled, "Temperature and Blackening Effects in Helical Tungsten Filaments."
Scope Note
The Benjamin Shackelford papers consist of lecture notes taken while Shackelford was a graduate student in Physics at the University of Chicago (1915-1917). The collection includes notes from classes given by Frederick Lindemann, Albert Abraham Michelson, Robert Andrews Millikan, Arthur Lunn, and Gilbert Bliss.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
Bliss, Gilbert Ames, 1876-1951; Cherwell, Frederick Alexander Lindermann, Viscount, 1886-1957; Lunn, Arthur C. (Arthur Constant), b. 1877; Michelson, Albert Abraham, 1852-1931; Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868-1953; Shackelford, Benjamin Estill; Lecture notes
INVENTORY
- Lindermann Notes, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Radiation Notes, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Vector Analysis Notes, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bliss, Complex Variables Notes, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Michelson, Physical Optics Notes, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Michelson, Electromagnetic Theory Notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Michelson, Electromagnetic Theory Notes, Spring 1915 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bliss, Definite Integrals Notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Milliken, Thermodynamics Notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Milliken, Kinetic Theory Notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lunn Notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Milliken, Electron Theory Notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alternating Currents Notes, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Michelson, Wave Motion Notes, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)